And Prezel and I, we met on a dating app
called Hinge. Uh, we're married now, so
that makes us unhinged.
People are confused by that. They're
like, "Wait, wasn't it Love at First
Sight?" And I'll admit, it wasn't even
Love at First website. So, I was on
Tinder, Bumble, Hinge. I even tried
LinkedIn,
but Prexel and I, we did meet online. We
met on a dating app. And, uh, whenever
people ask how we met, I do say that we
met through a friend. Uh, not because
I'm embarrassed, it's just I'm a
computer engineer, so I consider the
internet my friend.
People be like, "Wait, how did you two
get together?" It's like, "Oh, our
friend Al set us up."
Algorithm
together. And I appreciate dating apps
because Pretzel and I would not have met
if it wasn't for the apps because first
of all, uh, Pretzel is very attractive.
Like I never would have had the
confidence to like approach her out in
public or at a bar cuz I am not someone
who has game.
Like I don't even have practice.
I'm terrible. And I get awkward in
situations as well. I I'm awkward to be
around sometimes. Like I remember still
date number 47. First date number 47. We
uh agreed to do a morning coffee date,
which is the least romantic of all
dates. Uh you might as well go to the
DMV.
And she wanted some coffee. I want a
cake pop. So, I was like, "All right,
let's do it." And uh I get to the uh the
date a little bit early and I realized
that the coffee shop that we're going to
was inside of a building where the
entrance was a revolving door. And
normally I think revolving doors are
kind of fun. They can be a little
carousel ride, etc. Right? And so I was
normally excited by that, but this
morning that I was there, I was like,
"Wait a second. If I'm going to try to
be a gentleman, if I want to show that
I'm chiverous, am I supposed to go first
or second through the revolving door,
right? Because I was like, I know it's
ladies first, but you're also supposed
to get the door. And I don't think
you're supposed to stand there and spin
the door for them,
right? Just like voom.
Just wheel of fortune. Come on, hop in
whenever you're ready.
I don't think you're supposed to do
that. So, I didn't know what to do. So,
I asked my best friend. And I was like,
"Hey Google,
am I supposed to go first or second?" It
turns out, according to a British
chivalry guide, the answer to whether
you go first or second through revolving
door, the answer is both.
That's right. You are supposed to go in
the door, loop around,
and come out second.
Here's the thing about that little
factoid. It's that no one else knows
that.
Right? Cuz a date shows up. We have a
little bit of small talk outside and
then we start to walk in and I cut her
off a little bit cuz I want to be a
gentleman.
And I start going through the revolving
door and I get to about here and realize
she's turned around and now she's just
staring at me
confused and embarrassed. And people in
the coffee shop are like whispering and
pointing. And I had no choice but at
this point to just continue. And
one more loop and go home.
Sure, she was a nice person. I'll never
know,
right? So I'm awkward, right? So I
wasn't going to approach my wife at the
bar and we probably would have never met
through work either because like I do
this for a living. I do standup comedy.
and he asked to do keynote speaking,
talk about communication and leadership
and I have a TEDex talk which has more
than 10 million views on it only half of
which were from my mom
and you know some people think that I'm
funny and I read like all of the
comments on YouTube. I read like all of
them and some of them are positive and
some of them are not. Some of them are
interesting like one person was like you
look like a nerdy Neopatrick Harris.
Like do you need the word nerdy there?
Like I'm I'm nerdier than the guy that
played a kid Dr. Genius.
I don't know. Um I actually Neil Patrick
Harris is a little bit better than a
friend of mine recently told me that I
kind of look like US soccer star Megan
Rapino.
I think it's amazing, right? She's a
world champion, outspoken leader. I
think it's accurate, too, because you
know, we both have similar hair. We both
love soccer. We both get called ma'am on
the phone.
you know, the one person that uh some
people didn't like the talk. One person
said like he thinks he's funny. He's but
he's like wait for the next elevator
funny. That was one of the like that is
so specific, right? And was like maybe
it's a compliment. Maybe he's saying
that my you know my humor works on
different levels.
My per my favorite though my favorite
comment on uh online though was uh I
would pay to hear how this guy sounds on
helium.
No one wants that.
>> But the comments are really interesting
cuz some people love the talk, some
people don't. Some people are like,
"This guy is funny." People are like,
"This guy isn't funny. Best TED talk
ever. This was useless, brilliant,
witty, and entertaining. Go back to
engineering, please."
That's the thing. It's kind of like, you
know, just like dating in some ways. And
for me, I just try to follow the advice
of the great philosopher Taylor Swift,
right? Cuz haters going to hate hate
hate hate.
Just got to shake it off,
right? Cuz it is like dating. You got to
find people whose weird matches your
weird, whose sense of humor matches your
sense of humor. And when you find them,
you marry them. or you follow them at
Drew Tarvin on all social media
including YouTube, LinkedIn, Facebook
and I'm still on MySpace for some reason
as well.
Right. So, I do this for a living and my
wife Pretzel works for the UN for the
United Freaking Nations which is very
intimidating when you first start dating
someone. Uh I remember like pretty early
on when we were first dating, we were
having lunch together. She looked a
little stressed out and I was like, "Hey
pretzel, what's got you in a twist?
She was like, "Well, it's been a tough
morning. You know, I just got off of a
two-hour phone call with North Korea." I
was like, "Wow,
I'm sorry about the pretzel pun now."
And then she was like, "Wait a second.
You look stressed, too. What's going on
with you?" And I was like, "Also a tough
morning." You know, I I spent two hours
working on a pun.
In my defense, I feel like it was a
pretty good pun. Uh the pun was if you
catch mono twice does it become stereo
like that's worth two hours of effort.
Right. Right. And she laughed. Right.
And she liked and so we got together and
yeah like that's why I appreciate online
dating because we wouldn't have met if
it weren't for that thing. And and
Pretzel and I we met on a dating app
called Hinge. Uh we're married now, so
that makes us unhinged.
And uh Hinge is an interesting dating
app because it asks these like different
icebreaker questions before you get to
know someone a little bit. And so like
one of the questions like what's your
personal brand? And so I think my
personal brand is like coolish nerd,
right? Cuz I'm like clearly a nerd,
right? A friend of mine told me he's
like you don't have to tell people
you're a nerd. You can hear it in your
voice,
right? But I try to be cool, but I think
I try to do cool things for nerdy
reasons. Like, like I think the best way
to greet someone is like a fist bump. I
like a fist bump. But I like that
because I read in a peer-reviewed
journal article that is statistically
the least amount of germ transfer.
I'm like, coolish nerd. But the question
on hinge that got me into trouble was it
asked, "What do you like to do for
exercise?" And so I said that I run,
lift weights, and do yoga. Now, only one
of those is true.
You probably guess which one cuz like I
clearly don't lift weights. Like even my
doctor didn't believe me. I was asking
my doctor this year. I was like, "Hey,
what are the chances I actually put on
weight and put on muscle this year?" He
was like slim.
And I don't do yoga. The only reason why
I said that I did yoga is that I thought
it would make me sound like I was more
in touch with my emotions, right? Which
you all know I think of as data.
And uh but I put it in the app. I didn't
think too much of it. And Pretzel and I
go on our first date. We have a great
time. We go on our second date, third
date, fourth date, Pretzel is like, "You
know, one of the things that stood out
to me about your profile was that it
said that you do yoga. Not a lot of guys
do that." And so I was thinking for our
next date, we should go to a yoga class
together.
And so to tell her, I was like,
"Absolutely, that sounds amazing."
Right? Cuz I didn't want her to know
that I had lied, right? I didn't want to
end up in the downward-f facing
doghouse.
And so we go to yoga class the next day
and I pretty much immediately realize
that I'm in over my head literally
cuz I don't know any of the pose names
or anything or what I'm supposed to do.
At one point it felt like we're at the
zoo cuz there's like a lot of animal
poses, right? There is downward-f facing
dog and cat cow and pigeon pose and
scorpion and wolf of Wall Street and
crouching tiger hidden dragon and
animal. I did learn this quick pro tip.
I learned this one. Uh if you do go to
your first yoga class, just know that
whenever you do the animal poses, you
are not supposed to make the animal
noises.
I didn't know that. And I getting into
cat cow pose, right? And we're down
there. And so immediately I'm like, "All
right, here we go." And
no one else is doing that.
Now, for the rest of yoga class, I have
to pretend like meow is my yoga mantra.
Meow.
Yeah.
Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey. Hey.